Thank you for watching.
Thank you for your time today.
Best regards.
This time, I would like to ask you again about those two songs.
So, Katsurabon-san, when you received the offer, what did you think about it?
Mr. Sugimoto said, "This is the direction that the group is going right now,
I was wondering if you could give me a song like this one. Did you ask for this kind of song?
Yes, I did. From the beginning, I was also interested in Bar Tension and Mr. Daichi's ska,
I had an image of Bar Tension and Mr. Daichi's ska and rock-oriented songs from the beginning,
When I was asked to do a song with Bar Tension and Mr. Daichi...,
Oh, I get it. Then, I wanted something energetic,
I thought, "A song that everyone can ride together and get excited at a live performance,
But then I thought, "No, actually, there's a song called Oisa that's getting a lot of buzz right now,
I was shown the music video for it,
After I saw the music video, I thought, "I see,
I was shown the music video of the song, and after I thought, "I see," I listened to my bar tension and Daichi's ska song,
I was able to listen to WatakOI's demo song,
So you are still working on it?
That's right. When we were still making them before they were released to the world,
I heard the flow of those two songs,
I was impressed by what Bartention and Mr. Daichi were going to do together,
He told me that he wanted to send me the next song that would lead to the next song,
And the result was Yoimiya.
I was wondering how you would start the process of making a new song,
I was wondering what kind of place to start from,
Melody, chord progression, tone, rhythm, etc,
melody, chord progression, tone, rhythm, and so on,
Well, this may be a bit of an argument to begin with, but...,
I wonder where Kikuchi-san gets his musical inspiration from.
It is not limited to Yoimiya or the searchers this time,
I usually start with the beat,
I roughly determine the speed and groove of the music before deciding what to put on it,
Then, what will be put on top of that?
Then I start thinking about what to put on the beat and the chord progression.
For example, if it's a lingering or lonely part of a song, I'll start by thinking about what to put on it, or the chord progression,
For example, if it is a lingering or lonely part, the tempo should not be so fast, right?
Yes, that's right.
At first, I had the image of a more enjoyable festival,
But when I gave him the lyrics, he said they were a bit too childish.
I decided to make it more mature dance music,
I made the BPM a little slower,
The tone of the music was not EDM of a gakkira style,
I used a little bit more rounded and bouncy tones,
It was like adjusting the gradation little by little.
For example, the first verse of "Yoinya,
The first, second, and third cues.
The melody in that area is all there at the beginning,
I used this chamisen-like sound,
I had a melody that was traced in the melody,
But when it was time to mix, Mr. Sugimoto said, "I'm going to ask you to turn them all off,
Would you like me to erase all of them? He asked me if I wanted him to turn it all off.
The beat was completely muffled, and only the voice was on the track,
I was able to create a stoic verse,
It turned out to be a stoic verse.
The result was amazing,
The rawness of the voice was amazing,
I think I really liked that effect,
As a result, I was happy with the result.
It was good.
When I did that,
I was already playing it,
When I played it live, the sound was really crisp and clear,
I was thinking about whether I wanted it to be cool or easy to dance to,
I had a hard time deciding whether to go for coolness or ease of danceability,
I had a hard time deciding whether to go for coolness or ease of dancing,
But I knew I had to make a drastic decision like that.
I was surprised,
I was surprised to learn that such things happen in the mixing stage.
Yes, it does. Yes, it did.
Isn't it amazing?
Because mixing,
Mixing is the final step after everything has been decided,
It's not a balancing act.
So, it's all about the arrangement?
Yes, that's right.
It's like a dub mix all of a sudden.
Let's arrange it.
You remove it.
You remove the existence of the melody.
You put in an instrument that traces the melody,
It's a promise in idol music,It's also pretty much a promise in idol music,
It makes it easier to actually sing them at this live performance or something,
It's not a karaoke guide per se, but it makes the song sound like a karaoke guide,
It's not a karaoke guide, but it makes the song sound like a karaoke guide.
It makes my voice sound thicker, and so on,
On the contrary, the lack of it makes it easier to sing,
But without it, you can suddenly see the rawness of the voice and the good parts of the voice,
I can see the good parts of the voice,
I see what you mean,
I thought it would be better without it,
I thought it would be better without it.
As for what I was looking for, it was the next stage.
It's a great song, isn't it?
As for that song, I think it would be interesting if the setting was like this.
It was a little too weird.
There were some stories that I was given.
One of them is that during Yoimiya, it's the "haneyuteki" part of the festival.
So this time, I asked him to give us the upper side of the festival, the sunny side.
He said, "I would like to focus on one prefecture in Kyushu, which is 9 years old.
I asked for a song about Saga.
I said, "Okay, Saga. I said, "Okay, Saga.
We talked about various local specialties.
I knew that Saga is famous for its balloon festival, so it was a good idea.
Then the conversation suddenly jumped to Turkey.
We suddenly talked about Turkey when we talked about balloon festivals.
Suddenly, we went from hills to Turkey.
Let's make it to this day with Turkish color music.
That's right.
Turkish color music. I couldn't imagine that at all.
This subject is difficult, so I thought of a folk music that sounds close, a bit like Celtic music.
The lyrics are about a balloon festival in Saga. The lyrics are about the Saga Balloon Festival.
The result is a global music.
I want to go from the balloon to Turkey and then to Ireland.
It was like associative art.
It's like the LCC way of life.
From transit.
It was a genre of music I didn't know at all either,
I got the tendencies, like the local scales and the verses.
It was quite difficult to reproduce those things.
I listened to the music and reflected on how much I had annoyed Kenmoji.
After that, I said, "That's all right," with great speed.
I decided to make it another Kenmoji's way of saying "world music.
I told him that I thought there was another direction for world music.
About two or three days later, the Celtic music came out.
It was so good.
I was so excited that I listened to it by myself.
However, I was still bound by the music.
It's the same with Japanese instruments.
There is also the subject of including Celtic-esque music, but in the end, you have to include such things.
I still feel like, "No, don't be absurd.
Yes, that's right.
Well, I don't include Japanese instruments in what I'm looking for.
There are some koto (Japanese harp) sounds in the middle of the piece.
I thought it would be OK if I didn't include the melancholy of Japanese instruments as I did in Yoimiya.
I didn't want to include the melancholy sounds of Japanese instruments as much as I did in Yoimiya.
There was a kind of sound that would make your head explode.
I only added a little bit of that as an essence.
I also thought the melody of the song was really great.
The same notes keep coming in succession.
The same goes for the A melody and the chorus.
I thought that Khenburi-san had a bug. At first.
The same notes kept going on and on like a one-note 3rd note.
It was like "ten-ten-ten-ten-ten-ten.
I thought it was amazing.
How did you do that?
I thought it was interesting that everyone sings like a percussion instrument.
The chorus was written in the rhythm of "te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te te le.
I wanted to use that kind of rhythm, but it was too rhythmic and I couldn't get into the lyrics halfway through.
So I ended up with the lyrics about taking onomatopoeia along with me.
Tete-tete-tete!
Rhythm?
I had a lot of trouble when I was singing the lyrics, that's for sure.
Of course, I did some editing, but I don't want to be too frank about that.
I think that's the fun of editing.
Yes, it was a lot of work.
Yes, it was.
That's how it became such a percussive song.
The first half of the song
The first half of the song is different from the usual.
It was more like an extension of a rap song, with a little bit of melody added.
The rest of the song, I don't know how to say it, has a kind of drop, even if it is the chorus,Even if it is the chorus, it still has a drop-like quality to it,
After "Let's go looking for it," it's more like the real thing.
I guess you want people to dance to that part. Yes, I want people to dance to the fun side of dance music.
I was able to express a different side of dance music with "Yoimiya," so I wanted to create a completely different kind of dance music.
I tried to express a different side of dance music with Yoimiya.
So, I thought it might be an interlude, but I was sure it would be the chorus.
The interlude is the chorus, or rather, I feel that everyone is moving toward it.
I thought it was an interesting and unusual song, because the drum roll was building up toward the chorus.
I thought it was an interesting song, an unusual song.
I thought it was an interesting song, and I thought it was a different song.
I thought it was an interesting song because it was getting more and more exciting.
I think it's only when you have something like that that your ears and eyes are kept and the whole thing is kept alive.
There's a word for that... "pause"... "pause"... "pause"... "pause".
But you're right, the dance moves also add to the strangeness of the song.
Yes, that's right. I thought it was a little deformed.
The movement of the balloon eventually turns into a shadowless belt in the chorus.
So even if you go through England, you're still in the shadowless zone.
That song is amazing!
Some idols can't handle the parts without singing.
Some idols can't do anything about the parts that don't have a song, so they ask us not to do any drops or anything like that.
We often get such comments.
On the contrary, Mr. Sugimoto and Mr. and Mrs. Batechu tolerate it.
In fact, they want us to do so.
I remember that was the case at Yoimia.
When I said "yoimia part", I was asking for a favor.
I dared to leave that part blank.
I had asked him to answer this question in a previous interview.
I wanted to put something like a rap song by Wirouri in there.
I thought about putting something like a Japanese rap song.
We couldn't come up with a good idea even though the deadline was already approaching.
But it's cool to listen to just the sound,
We thought we could show it in a dance.
We also had the opportunity to work with Airman.
We also had a chance to play with Airman, and that became a part where everyone at the concert could hit it with an okashiwa and ask him to do something.
We were able to have that kind of fun again.
That's right.
If you think about it from the premise of a live performance, I think the problem of what to do during the non-singing time is a big one.
But Airman and everyone else accepts that.
Rather, they enjoy the extra time.
I think that idols who are in front of the order of the audience will make time for a goal and response with the audience,
I think the idols in the front of the line would make time for the audience to get excited, like doing goal and response with all their might.
Or they would have a quick MC-type moment.
Many people do that,
I wonder if it would be possible to create a part where people can enjoy the performance and give their impressions of it.
So, I have probably done the Yoimiya part with Airman,
In the search, I diverge a little bit from that part with the no-shadow belt movement.
He suggested a part that would be physically exhausting.
I thought it was great.
Everyone was playing in a state of tension,
I felt that everyone was playing in a state of tension.
I was thinking about the choreography,
How much do the songwriters expect the choreography?
How much do you think about the choreography when you are writing a song?
Don't you think about it when you make a song?
I don't think so...
I don't think so much. On the contrary, I don't really think about it until after I've finished making the song.
I'm just waiting to see what kind of choreography will be used, or what kind of music video I can enjoy.
I'm waiting to see what kind of choreography and music video I can enjoy.
The music is only one part of it. Music is only one part of it.
I would never be able to make that kind of leap of imagination on my own, so I enjoy watching it accumulate and accumulate.
That's it, isn't it? When you see a music video, it's like a legendary monster of the island. I see. You see things that you shouldn't see.
That's the image I have. And there is that. After all, SUGIMA is here.
I feel like I have to challenge myself in various ways. I don't know how to say that I have to, but I wonder if it is okay to take on challenges. I guess so.
Yes, I think so. If I am not given a certain framework or theme, I am at a loss if I am asked to create completely freely.
My way of life as a writer becomes ingrained in me. If you ask me to give you a theme, I am at a bit of a loss.
If you give them a challenge, you can create a puff piece. It is easier to work with restrictions, which is why we are given such interesting settings.
If you are going to ask Kenmochi to do something, you have to prepare an interesting theme. That is possible.
So, thank you very much for sharing with us the secret stories behind the production. Thank you very much.
Will you write more Batten songs in the future? I can't say no.
I can't wait to hear what you have to say.
I am really looking forward to your future development. Thank you very much.
I am also looking forward to receiving new settings and thinking of new, challenging, and reckless ideas.
I look forward to receiving your continued support.
Thank you very much for your continued support. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.